MELANIE VILLELA

melanienvillela@gmail.com

https://melanievillela.github.io/

1523 W. Sam Houston Pkwy. S. Houston, Texas 77042

713-366-2532

Web Developer

Looking to fulfill a role using my education and skills as a web developer. I am currently learning AWS Cloud Development. I have experience using multiple front-end frameworks. For the past 2 years I have been working as a freelancer and contractor doing web development but I am looking for a full time position. I am team player that is eager to learn new technologies and isn't afraid of a challenge.

EDUCATION

University of Houston • Mechanical Engineering

• Front End Web Developer
Udacity

• AWS Cloud Developer

SKILLS

•	HTML5	~	CSS3	•	BOOTSTRAP	~	MATERIALIZE
~	BULMA	•	EJS	•	JQUERY	•	JAVASCRIPT
~	REACT	•	NEXTJS	•	GATSBY	•	NODE
•	EXPRESS	•	PHP	•	WORDPRESS	•	PYTHON
~	FLASK	•	FIREBASE	•	MONGODB	•	GIT
~	WEB SCRAPING	•	RESTFUL API	•	UI/UX	•	ILLUSTRATOR
•	PHOTOSHOP	~	LIGHTROOM	•	HEROKU	~	AWS S3

EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer

Colored Pixel Studios

2019 - 2020

I worked part time on a contract basis as a front end developer for a boutique web design studio. I worked using a variety of frameworks and libraries including React, Wordpress, Next JS and Gatsby to build out the front end according to customer specifications. I also helped in the design process as necessary using Photoshop to help create mock-ups to prepare for customer presentations.

Web DeveloperFreelancer2018 - 2019

I worked as a freelancer creating landing pages for various businesses and making updates to current WordPress sites including layout and design modifications. I mainly used Bootstrap, Materialize, Wordpress, React, Firebase and Heroku. I also helped customers connect their domain to their hosting and deploy the site for them.

Mechanical Designer

Expro Group

2013 - 2020

I worked as a full time as a mechanical designer in the oil and gas industry. Primarily used Solidworks.

Mechanical Drafter

Radoil

2007 - 2011

I worked as a mechanical drafter in the oil and gas industry. Primarily used AutoCAD Mechanical.